Luke Vella

UI Developer & Designer

lukevella.com hello@lukevella.com Malta, MST4543

Summary

I am a front-end developer with over 5 years of professional experience. Most of my work has revolved around creating large scale single-page applications and responsive user-interfaces. I enjoy staying on the bleeding edge of technologies and discovering better and more efficient ways to improve my workflow. My strong design background allows me to both communicate my thoughts effectively when working in a team but also work independently.

Work Experience

2014 - 2015 ArtWalk artwalk.city

Freelance Developer

Developed a <u>CMS</u> built on top of <u>Wordpress</u> to deliver complex data using a <u>RESTful</u> API. Developed an iOS app using the <u>AFNetworking</u> library to consume and present data from the API.

2012 - 2014 **Zeepex** zeepex.com

Frontend Developer & Designer

Designed and developed a <u>single-page application</u> using object-oriented and modular javascript. Developed an <u>isomorphic</u> javascript plugin that given some basic information could find social media profiles belonging to a user in real-time.

2009 - 2011 AWHPoker

Frontend Developer & Designer

Created a web application that interfaced with the gaming network's <u>SOAP API</u> to display information from the network's back-office to the poker room's users. Responsible for the design and development of multiple <u>internationalized</u> websites and marketing tools.

Education

2009 - 2012 University of Malta

B.Sc. Computer Science & Artificial Intelligence

Projects

2015 **Rallly** rallly.co

Web Application

Rallly is a collaborative scheduling service that helps people vote on a date to host an event.

2013 Freeshot freeshotapp.com

iOS App

Freeshot is an iOS app for the Dribbble design community. It has received over 25,000 downloads on the App Store.

Skills & Expertise

Specialities

Web Applications, iOS Apps, User Interfaces, User Experience.

Languages

Object-Oriented Javascript, HTML5, CSS3, SASS/SCSS, Node.js, PHP, Swift, Objective-C, Java.

Frameworks & Libraries

Angular.js, Express.js, Backbone.js, Marionette.js, Require.js, Compass, Bourbon, jQuery, Yii, Codelgniter.

Apps, Tools & Misc.

Git, Gulp, Bower, Apache, Unix, Atom, Sketch, Xcode, MySql, MongoDB, Photoshop.